Now I want to talk about meditation number
10.
We have to discuss 27 before we
go into Ried. Meditation number 10 is
called Earth, the foundation and the one
that ultimately succeeds in following.
And the first thing, as I just said, is to
say to plant the seeds
with patience and not to buy younger ones.
This worldview,
taking refuge in this way, is necessary for all
future Buddhist practices, and
that has to be in place before you
can take the Tatra vows,
before you
can take monk or nun vows or participate live. It was
besides the struggles, they are all based on
the refuge principle. So, in the
steps of taking refuge, these
simple vows are like the earth
and all spaces and all the flowers that
grow from it.
They come from there, and through banker wants to
emphasize very strongly.
So, for example, I planted theirs, namely
their bulbs. They grow at my home,
a very
light yellow and then a very light blue.
I just
photographed them; they are so beautiful, and the earth
where I live is almost  90 percent is just
stones.
It's terrible when I
take out a stone because then the whole soil collapses.
The soil is hopeless. It
takes three hours to
dig a small hole for a rose in Flanders,
almost an hour there, and then I plant
these bulbs and then these colors come
out. And I can't even
imagine how these colors could grow out of this stony soil.
How could they, so to speak, pull
these things out of the stony soil,
pull this nourishment out,
since there's no color in the soil,
it's just dusty, dark
color. And then I put in a stupid bulb,
and then this bulb pulls the color
under the light purple. Of
course, it's only in bloom
and not in humility, and that's strange.
And for banks, it should say that it's the
same at the refuge. You take good ones to the gorge,
and then all the
other luck will also go well, and
things should happen, and there will be
very beautiful, even difficult
practices.
Maybe celebrations will take place because of the refuge.  It's like,
so to speak, the chemical that
makes everything bloom, all the other
facts, all the other loved ones, and I
've depicted an apple tree here. Whether
the rest of your Buddhist practice
is successful depends on the
refuge vow, which is like
the earth,
so it's like the foundation. The
refuge was successful, it's like the foundation.
If you do this meditation, then you
could think about all the practices: yoga,
meditation, studies. And if you approach all of that with refuge,
then
your yoga will be good, your meditation will
be good, and your studies
and, of course, your service to others
will be good.
But if your refuge isn't strong,
if your earth isn't strong, then it wo
n't be any different. So, I have to
tell you something about my foot wise now, for example, why do
gangsters sometimes get rich, like mafia
gangsters? Why can they get rich in
Vancouver? Right, then we could
n't actually get rich,
and I call that bird [ __ ], and
why do people ask me, "Do you call it that?"
And there's a tree that comes
from China, and it's called...  May
mulberry trees, and you need them
because the two worms that eat normal
leaves, and that's why you need them, that
's the only thing they like, and they
're more picky than me, and
someone brought the maypoles to Arizona for
many years, it was a secret, and at one point it was
even punishable by death, and if you had a
maypole once, and and and the
thrifty ones, they were smuggled from China, in someone's hat back then,
but anyway,
now they're very common
in Arizona, and we
kids climbed them, and they're
great because they need a lot of
water, and they make little purple
mulberries. I always wanted to have a
tree like that, but my partner says
they plant too many trees, they make too much, so to speak,
in order on the ground,
and once I saw a man
who was only so tall, and what is that, and
she said that's actually a
maypole, only so tall, almost the land. No, no, no, I didn't, I didn't,
I didn't do that, so
it must just be stupid to build
because the birds, the elves, the mulberries
And then we didn't
digest them very well, and then they were
excreted again, and then the
mulberry tree came about, and they
grew quite quickly, and so
I'm talking about my good karma, as
I can quickly see when it's warm, and
my partner said, okay, you have to
transplant it very quickly.
I simply divided the root, and
then it will die, and then I
asked if I could plant it in the garden, in
the back garden, and that was
okay, and there it has
now grown to three meters tall, and then
yes, and then the little ones came, so to speak, rats,
and they gnawed off the roots,
and
now, after they nibbled on the roots,
the
foundation for this tree has been removed,
and now, when I touched it, it changed its clothes,
and if I shake it now, the
roots are simply gone; they
gnawed off the roots. And now
I found out from my partner, I have to tell you, we were
outside, and he said
yes, and now it looks bad for
this tree, so I have to pray for this tree.
[Music]
So what I'm trying to say is, you
need a foundation. Without
the roots, you have
nothing. Without the roots, it looks like something,
but in reality, you have
nothing. And it's the same with practice.
If the words aren't right, then
you have nothing. Then your
practice collapses. It was really very disappointing.
I touched it, and it
just bent over.
And your practice will be the same if
you don't know about refuge.
You'll collapse right away.
Choose it, and it's the same with yoga.